红宝石
的空间
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
Husky
校对
依依
特效
presisco
压制
哦 来了一个!石榴 许个愿吧!
Ooh -- there's one! Garnet, you gotta make a wish!
好吧
All right.
闭上眼
Close your eyes.
全都闭上
All of them.
好吧好吧
Okay, okay.
现在许个愿望，别告诉我是什么
Now make your wish, but don't tell me what it is.
石榴 你许了什么愿?
Garnet, what did you wish for?
我的愿望是
I wished...
再来一颗流星 这样你就可以许愿了
for another shooting star, so that you could make a wish.
哦我天
Oh, my gosh!
石榴 愿望实现了!
Garnet, it worked!
那个流星...是在尖叫吗
Is that star... screaming?
那是啥?!
What was that?!
是脐脐!
It's Navy!
是个红宝石
That's a ruby.
你不记得了吗?我给她们都起了名
Don't you remember? I gave them all names.
这只叫脐脐，因为她宝石在肚脐上
This one's Navy, 'cause her gem is on her navel.
哦 我才明白过来
Oh. I finally get it.
哦 求求你
Oh, please, oh, please!
别把我送回母星!
Don't make me go back to Homeworld!
我想和你们一起住在这里!
Oh, I just want to stay here with you!
这...还真出乎预料呢
This... is a surprise.
你想住在地球上?
You want to live on Earth?
对啊!其他红宝石都对我很坏
Yeah! All the other rubies are mean to me.
我就想找一个能做自己的地方
I just want to be somewhere I can be myself.
我们那么对你 你不生气吗?
And you're not mad at us from before?
你是指什么?
What do you mean?
你懂的 比如骗你去打棒球那次
You know, about tricking you into playing baseball.
棒球很好玩啊!
That was fun!
还有那次紫晶扮成铁石英骗你们
Or when Amethyst pretended to be Jasper.
我得承认 那个骗局挺机智的
I gotta admit, that was pretty clever.
还有那次我把你们送进了太空
Or when we blasted you all out into space and stole your ship
还偷了你们的太空船?
so you'd be stranded forever?
这个 我们当时在战斗嘛 可以理解
Well, we were fighting, so it's understandable.
我不明白
I don't know about this.
她不是想用匕首戳你来着
She tried to stab you in space.
那是眼宝 不是脐脐
That was Eyeball, this is Navy.
事实上 她一直都是最可爱的那个
She always seemed really nice, actually!
谢谢夸奖
Hey, thanks!
还有 从天上坠入人间的红宝石
And, you know, a ruby falling from the sky,
发现新世界的美丽--
discovering this beautiful world --
这不就是你给我讲的故事吗
sounds a lot like a story you told me once.
哦 别说了
Oh, stop.
啊!从这儿起就交给我吧!
Ah! Let me take it from here!
我知道有个地方绝对适合她!
I know exactly where she'll fit in!
好吧 史蒂文宇宙 施展你的魔法吧
All right, Steven Universe, go work your magic.
总算有个可以许愿的星星了!
Finally! There's a star to wish on!
橄榄石!青金石!
Peridot, Lapis!
-史蒂文!-史蒂文!
-Steven! -Steven!
还有南瓜!我可没把你忘了!
And Pumpkin! Can't forget you!
看看你 又回来了
Well, well, back again.
你和我们一起住在这儿就好了嘛
You should just move in with us at this point.
其实 可能不是我
Actually, maybe not me,
但我知道有其他人想在这里住哦!
but I know someone else who might be interested!
你好!我是脐脐，母星来的难民!
Hi! I'm Navy, a refugee from Homeworld!
就像你们一样!哈哈哈!
Just like you guys! Ha ha ha!
这个...
So, uh...
你什么时候来地球的?
When did you show up on Earth?
就今天!
Today!
新室友!
New barnie!
啥?!不行 等等
What?! No, hold on.
至少先商量一下吧?
Can we talk about this first?
对啊!是是是 当然了!
Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah, of course!
我最爱商量了!
I love talking!
哈?
Huh?
史蒂文 这根本说不通
Steven, this makes no sense.
她为什么会想住在这儿?
Why would she want to live here?
我们一直对她很坏 她肯定恨我们才对
We've been awful to her. She must hate us.
她不恨我们啊
She doesn't, though.
给她次机会吧
Give her a chance.
她是我们这边的了
She's on our side now.
这么容易?哇
Just like that? Wow.
没可能
There's no way.
这个 你们俩不也是想在这里建立新生活
Well, you guys wanted to start a new life here, too.
她肯定也想啊
It can totally happen!
就算她想待在这里
Even if she wants to be here,
她也理解不了这里的生活
she doesn't know what she's getting into.
地球生活真的很迷
Life on Earth is really confusing.
我都花了好长时间才适应
It took me a long time to get used to it.
我现在还在适应
I'm still getting used to it.
但是...
But...
我们可以教她啊!
we can show her the way!
我是说 我们已经跨过这个坎了
I mean, we've been through the ringer on all this stuff.
我们可以分享下自己的经验嘛
It'll be cool to share what we've learned.
你也知道 我们肯定会教得很好的
And, you know, I think we'd be really good at it.
好吧
Okay.
行 我试一试 但是我们得慢慢来
Okay, I'll give it a try, but we'll have to take it slow.
棒!
Yeah!
肯定很棒的 我就知道!
This will be great, I just know it!
谢谢你们!
Thank you!
现在你是个地球种了!
So you're an Earthling!
这又意味着什么呢?
But what does that mean?
答案就是...
Well, the answer is...
谁知道呢?
who knows?!
这就是地球的美丽之处啦!
And that's the beauty of Earth!
这里的一切都不合逻辑!
Nothing here makes sense!
这就是为什么你需要我们!
But that's why you have us now!
喜欢上地球一开始可能很难
It might be hard to like Earth at first.
这里就是...
It is where...
那些糟糕的事发生的地方
a bunch of bad stuff happened.
我喜欢这儿!这儿好阳光啊!
I love it! It's so sunny!
啊 对的!
Ah, yes!
太阳--永不熄灭地燃烧...直到熄灭为止
The sun -- ever-burning... until it's not.
这个星球上有气象变化
This planet has weather,
有时候很令人困惑和恐慌
which can be confusing and alarming.
现在是晴天 但是待会可能会下雨
It's sunny now, but it could always rain later.
什么是"下雨"?
What is rain?
就像--等下!我可以给你演示
It's like -- oh, wait! I can just show you.
我知道有点奇怪 但是--
I know it's a bit strange, but --
天空在哭泣啊!
The sky is crying!
她喜欢这个!脐脐喜欢这个!
She likes it! Navy likes it!
哦!
Oh!
一颗有阴有晴的星球!
A planet that's not always sunny.
就好像它...总是在变化!
It's almost like it's always...changing!
真是太美了!
That's so beautiful!
是啊!就是这样!
Yeah! Exactly!
哇!
Wow!
这已经是《地球生活》第97章的内容了
That's, like, chapter 97 of Earth stuff.
看来我们手上有个超前的学生呢!
Looks like we got an advanced student on our hands!
是啊 不假
Yeah. No kidding.
这是我们的"宝石洞"
This is our "gem cave."
青金石不喜欢我用这个称呼 我就没用
Lapis hates when I call it that, so I don't.
这个仓库挺大的
The barn's pretty big,
你可以随便找个角落
so you can have one of the corners.
都是你的了
Make it your own.
听起来好棒啊
That sounds so nice.
一个角落 太美好了
Any corner would be lovely.
你可以到处转转
You should have a look around.
哦!这是干嘛的?
Ohh! What's this for?
这是个吊床 可以从上面掉下来的床
That's a hammock. It's a bed you fall out of.
我喜欢在上面睡觉
It's where I like to sleep.
我不需要睡觉 但是我喜欢睡觉
I don't have to do it, but I like to do it --
你知道的 放空一切 然后--
you know, turn off for a bit and --
打呼噜 就像这样
Snore. Like this!
呼噜!
Snore!
哇!听起来好炫!我该怎么做?
Wow! Sounds groovy! How do I start?
这个很难解释
That one's really hard to explain.
你就躺在那儿 闭上眼
You lay down somewhere and close your eyes.
然后什么都不想--或者什么都想
And think about nothing -- or everything.
但是可能需要一段时间
But it may take you a little while
你才能感到放松然后--
to feel comfortable enough to --
看来你已经掌握了
Looks like you've got it.
这是我们的有机地球田地
And here's our organic Earth farm.
我们脚下的土壤中充满了资源
The ground beneath our feet is teeming with resources
可以喂饱这些庄稼
which feed the growing crops around us.
不用费心和玉米交流了
Don't bother talking to the corn.
它们听不见
It can't hear you.
你一开始可能会感到植物很陌生 别担心
Plants may seem strange to you at first, but don't worry,
你也不需要立刻就学会喜欢上所有事物
you don't have to love everything right away.
我喜欢植物!哦!
I love plants! Oh!
这个 那南瓜呢?
Well, what about Pumpkin?
你喜欢南瓜吗?
Do you love Pumpkin, too?
我爱南瓜!
I love Pumpkin!
噫 南瓜之吻!
Ew, Pumpkin kisses!
那泥土呢?你也喜欢泥土吗?
Well, what about dirt? Do you love the dirt, too?
泥土是什么?
What's dirt?!
我喜欢泥土!
I do love the dirt!
我们呢?你对我们什么感觉?
So what about us? How do you feel about us?
你们是最棒的!
You guys are the best!
谢谢!谢谢你们!谢谢你们让我加入!
Thank you, thank you! Thank you all for taking me in!
哦!我们肯定会成为最好的朋友的!
Oh! We're gonna be the best of friends!
但是我们是敌人啊!
But we were just enemies!
你不记得了?你为什么不生气?!
Don't you remember? Why don't you get mad?!
我想我就算试着生气
I think even if I really tried,
我还是不会生气的
that's the one thing I can't do.
哦 得了吧!
Oh, come on!
我做错了什么?
Did I do something?
可要更复杂一些吧
I think it might be more complicated than that.
你待在这里欣赏植物吧
Why don't you stay here and admire more of the plants?
-青金石!-青金石!
-Lapis! -Lapis!
-你在哪?!-她简直...
-Where are you?! -She's just...
她看起来好像喜欢我们
It's just like she's fine with us,
就像啥事没有一样
like there's no problem.
青金石 你还好吗?
Lapis, are you okay?
不好 我有很严重的问题
No. Something is seriously wrong with me.
我花了那么长时间才喜欢上这个星球
It took me so long to learn to like this planet.
嘿 没人说非得那么着急啊
Hey, no one said there's a rush!
脐脐就是能很快喜欢上所有人和所有事的那种
Navy just loves everyone and everything right away.
她没防备 也没恐惧 我理解不了
She has no guard, no fear. I just don't get it.
为什么对她来说那么容易 对我来说那么难?
Why is it so easy for her, when it was so hard for me?
哦 不!
Oh, no!
我不是有意让你们伤心的!
I didn't mean to make anyone upset!
哦!我还是最好离开吧!
Oh! Maybe I should just go!
-嗷 脐脐 -不 是我的问题
-Aw, Navy. -No, no, it's my problem.
我不想让你觉得你不属于这里的
I didn't mean to make you feel like you don't belong here.
是啊 你在这儿就很好!
Yeah, you should stay!
哦 大伙儿!我太高兴了!
Ooh, you guys! I'm so glad!
我也不知道我还能去哪
I don't know where I would go anyway.
没了飞船我哪儿也去不了
I can't go anywhere without my ship.
那儿其实是我唯一的归属了
That's the only place I've ever really belonged, anyways.
我太想它了!哦!
I miss it so much! Oh!
脐脐!你的飞船在我们这儿!
Navy! We have your ship!
就在那里!
It's right over there!
在这儿?哇!
You do? Wow!
我都没注意到它在那儿!
I didn't even notice it there!
也许你可以...让我们参观下你的工作?
Maybe you could, uh... show us the ropes?
我太乐意了!
I would love that!
哦吼吼吼!
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
简直完美!
This is perfect!
水晶宝石们总算有个飞行员了!
The Crystal Gems finally have a pilot!
一切都好 是吧?
Things are going okay now, huh?
是啊 一切都好!
Yeah. Yeah, they are!
嘿 史蒂文 按一下你后面那个按钮
Hey, Steven, hit that button behind you,
我来展示下这架宝贝儿的能力
and I'll show you what this baby can really do!
呃 你是说这个按钮?
Uh, you mean the one right here?
是!就是那个!
Yeah! That's the one!
我要按了!
I'm gonna press it!
脐脐!你在吗?!
Navy! Hello?!
脐脐!飞船好像出问题了了!
Navy, I think something went wrong with the ship!
唯一的问题是...
The only thing wrong...
你们竟然还在扒着
is that you're still holding on.
等下!这么久以来 你的唯一目的就是太空船?
Wait! This whole time, all you wanted was your ship?
你一开始偷走不就好了吗!
You could have just stolen it to begin with!
我当然可以啊
I could have done that.
但是这样一来 我又怎么
But then I would never have gotten to see
欣赏你们这些
the look on your face
被你们最可爱的红宝石骗之后的傻脸呢
when you were tricked by your favorite little ruby!
-啥?-嘿!
-What?! -Hey!
我听不见你们在说啥!
I can't hear what's happening!
脐脐是在给我们展示大海吗?
Is Navy showing us the ocean?
哦!这样效果还挺棒呢!
Oh! 'Cause this is a heck of a way to do it!
你个肮脏的小...
You dirty, little...
白白!
Bye-bye!
快 青金石!她要跑了!
Quick, Lapis, she's getting away!
我一直都是对的!
I was right!
没人能那么心地善良的
No one could be that well-adjusted!
石榴!
Garnet!
至少心思没白费
It was still worth a shot.